Hello English learners. Welcome
back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
intermediate level lesson
talking about appearances.
That's right. We are going to
change or somebody wants to
change their appearance and
they're going to have surgery.
Well, before we get started,
let's look at what kind of
surgery they're having in
today's vocabulary preview.
Very capillary preview.
Alright, so today we're going
to be talking about
plastic surgery specifically.
Plastic surgery. So why plastic?
I have no idea. I don't either
know. Well, basically plastic
surgery is, you know, the
surgery for your appearance, right?
It's not really for health reasons.
That's right. And sometimes
they add things to you.
Sometimes they take things away,
but they're not for your health.
They're not for your heart or your lungs.
Right. It's for your appearance.
And also called cosmetic surgery, right?
It's right. We'll be hearing
that later, but cosmetic
means having to do with
your appearance like cosmetics.
Right. Exactly. Alright, so we're
going to be talking about this.
Let's listen to our dialogue for
the first time and we'll be back.
What are you doing?
Look at me. I look so old.
I look as if I was 30.
Come on. Stop being so vain.
You look great. You are beautiful.
Yes, I am, but I think it's
time for some plastic surgery.
I'm tired of these wrinkles
and sagging skin. See?
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
You're 25. Stop being ridiculous.
Besides, I think that people
who get Botox have face
lifts or tummy tucks look
weird. Doesn't look natural.
Whatever. I think I'm
going to get liposuction
and a nose job and some
breast implants as well.
I think you need to get
brain surgery. I honestly don't
think you need cosmetic
surgery. You look amazing.
I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this.
I just want to feel better about
myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to
do that. You're fine the way you are
and you have guys drooling all
over you. Plus plastic surgery hurts.
Really? Yeah. When I got my nose
job, I was black and blue for a week.
All right, we're back. So yeah, I think
this girl really wants to get this surgery.
But she doesn't
seem to know why.
She's just like, "I'm in a
bad mood. I want surgery.
" That's the worst reason. And
it's pretty painful for what I hear.
Expensive and painful
and potentially dangerous.
But we can talk
about that at the end.
All right, so why don't we
start with the words that we
saw that are all related to
surgery in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay, well, this first one
might be the reason for surgery,
not necessarily a kind of
surgery. If someone is vain.
Okay, so if a person is vain, this
is an adjective. That means that
they are very, they care too
much about their appearance, right?
Right, and they care so much that
they only care about themselves.
So do I look good? I love my
face, my eye. I look so good,
so a person who is vain
thinks very highly of themselves.
Okay, very good. And well,
this person I think wanted to
get surgery as well because
she said she had wrinkles.
Okay, wrinkles are
little lines on your face.
So maybe on your forehead
or next to your mouth.
And generally, when we get older,
people get more and more of these.
Right, so you would say you have
even you have wrinkly skin when
you're in the bathtub for too
long and you look in your hands.
They look like raisins,
you have wrinkly skin.
That's right, wrinkles
are little lines in your skin.
All right, and well, you have wrinkles
as you said around your mouth and eyes.
And sometimes under your eyes,
you also have some sagging skin.
Or under your chin?
Under your chin as well, yeah.
That's right, so sagging means
coming down means it's heavy.
It's like hanging, so
sagging, something sags.
It's heavy, it pulls down.
But if you have sagging
skin that means your skin
is no longer tight, it's
kind of loose and it hangs.
Falling off your face. Okay,
and well, a new popular
treatment that is not
really surgery is this Botox.
That's right, so Botox is something
that women and some men
do every couple of months I
think and they have to get shots.
Right, they're like injections.
That's right, and they tighten your skin.
And so you can get Botox in
your face, your forehead or your
eyes and it makes you look
younger for a couple of months.
I've heard that they also put them in
their lips to make them like fuller, right?
That's right.
And sometimes you can
say that someone's had
too much Botox because
they can no longer smile.
Or they can't stop smiling.
Exactly.
And well, very related to this is
also when people get a face lift.
Okay, a face lift.
So that means that a doctor, a plastic
surgeon, will tighten the skin on your face so
he'll pull your eyes and the skin next to
your ears to make your face look younger.
Right, so that's called a face lift.
So it's kind of take away those
wrinkles, right, or the sagging skin.
Right, lift means to pull
up the opposite of sag.
Very good.
All right, so this dialogue has a lot
of rich vocabulary related surgery.
So why don't we listen
to our dialogue again?
And we'll be back
with the second part of
language take away to
explain a little bit more.
What are you doing?
Look at me, I look so old.
I look as if I was 30.
Come on.
Stop being so vain.
You look great.
You are beautiful.
Yes, I am, but I think it's
time for some plastic surgery.
I'm tired of these
wrinkles and sagging skin.
See?
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
You're 25.
Stop being ridiculous.
Besides, I think that people who get Botox
have face lifts or tummy tucks look weird.
Doesn't look natural.
Whatever.
I think I'm going to get liposuction and a
nose job and some breast implants as well.
I think you need to get brain surgery.
I honestly don't think
you need cosmetic surgery.
You look amazing.
I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this.
I just want to feel better about
myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to do that.
You're fine the way you are and
you have guys drooling all over you.
Plus plastic surgery hurts.
Really?
Yeah.
When I got my nose job, I
was black and blue for a week.
Alright, we're back.
So what other surgical
procedure is in store for us?
Well, now the big ones.
So we've left the face and we're
talking about the rest of the body.
The first one is a tummy tuck.
Okay, so a tummy tuck.
Well, what is that exactly?
Well, let's look at these
two words by themselves
because maybe tummy
people have heard before.
This is another way to say stomach.
Usually children say tummy.
My tummy hurts.
And doctors they'll say stomach.
But the name of the surgery is tummy tuck
because tuck means to put in or to fold.
And so my mom used
to say tuck in your shirt.
You know when your shirt comes out of your
hands and that means you put it back in.
Well, a tuck means to
fold your stomach under.
It means to make your
stomach look smaller and
they put staples or I
think they sew you up.
Yeah, they sew you up.
It's pretty painful, right?
I've heard that.
Usually this is because somebody
got a liposuction, for example.
And that's our next word, liposuction.
Okay, lipo, that's kind of fat, right?
Yeah.
And suction means to pull like a vacuum.
Right.
So that's basically what they do.
They open the person
up and kind of use a sort
of vacuum type device
and suck all the fat
out of the stomach or
the balcony areas, you
know, the love handles
that are also called.
And this way they
remove all this excess fat.
And because they do this, sometimes the
skin since it's been stretched out because
you were a little bit fat, they need to
do, they need to have a tummy tuck.
That means to hide the extra skin.
Extra skin, to kind of hide it.
So these two procedures actually go hand
in hand because maybe if you're very fat,
you get a liposuction, but that
doesn't solve your problem because
now you have all these, all these
sagging skin off your stomach.
That's right.
So you have to have a tummy tuck as well.
All right.
So yeah, very, very dangerous
procedure I've heard as well, right?
Yeah.
And they usually only do it
with people who are very, very fat.
Right.
That means dangerously
fat because if you do it
on a skinny person, you
could really hurt them.
Yeah.
Of course, fat is also
necessary for our bodies.
All right.
So now moving back up to the
face again, a very common procedure.
I think one of the most
common ones is a nose job.
A nose job, and so nose
job is very colloquial.
You'll hear this on the TV.
Nose job means to
fix someone's nose, to
change the shape or
appearance of their nose.
And so oftentimes people with
really big noses want smaller noses.
Right.
And so the doctor will take some
bone away and we'll put the skin back.
Yes, that's right.
So this is called a nose job or formerly
known as like a nose surgery, right?
That's right.
Rhino plasty.
And actually I've heard
it's very painful because
they have to break your
nose before they fix it.
Exactly.
Wow.
I can't believe people do this.
All right.
And well, one of the very common ones among
women, most likely, is our breast implants.
That's right.
So breast implants, am I
allowed to say boob job?
Yeah, you can.
Well, the very common
phrase for this is boob job.
Boob is a very colloquial term for breasts.
And breast implants are, well, an implant
is something that you put inside something.
Okay.
And so a breast implant
is a piece of silicone.
So it's like plastic, but it's
more like a liquid plastic.
Yeah, just imagine like this big plastic
bag with like gel, right, inside of it.
And they put that inside a woman's
chest to make her breasts bigger.
Right.
So these are very, very popular
surgeries, breast implants.
Right.
Exactly.
I guess many models
and many, many types,
different types of women
get breast implants.
That's right.
And the verb there is to get.
So she had, she got breast implants.
Right.
Because they're things.
Very good.
All right.
So why don't we listen
to our dialogue for the last
time and we'll be back
to talk a little bit more.
What are you doing?
Look at me.
I look so old.
I look as if I were 30.
Come on.
Stop being so vain.
You look great.
You are beautiful.
Yes, I am.
But I think it's time for
some plastic surgery.
I'm tired of these
wrinkles and sagging skin.
See?
I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
You're 25.
Stop being ridiculous.
Besides, I think that people who get Botox
have facelifts or tummy tucks look weird.
Doesn't look natural.
Whatever.
I think I'm going to get
liposuction and a nose job.
And some breast implants as well.
I think you need to get brain surgery.
I honestly don't think
you need cosmetic surgery.
You look amazing.
I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this.
I just want to feel better about
myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to do that.
You're fine the way you are.
And you have guys drooling all over you.
Plus, plastic surgery hurts.
Really?
Yeah.
When I got my nose job, I
was black and blue for a week.
All right, we're back.
So as you mentioned, all of these surgeries
are very painful and very expensive, right?
They are.
The plastic surgery industry is huge.
And I was just reading an article that
said that redoes are becoming very popular.
So there are doctors who perform redoes.
That means redo a surgery.
That's right.
They're fixing other other surgeries
because oftentimes, you know, people go in.
They say, I want a nose job.
They get a nose job.
And then it's not the nose they wanted.
And so they have doctors now who
specialize in fixing former surgeries.
Wow.
I've heard also a lot
about the plastic surgery
tourism industry where
people get offered a package,
for example, to go to countries like
Argentina where they have good doctors.
And it's very inexpensive compared
to the states to get plastic surgery.
And it's also popular now
in Asia, I believe they're
traveling to Hong Kong
to get plastic surgery done.
Interesting.
Yeah, I know.
It's one of those things that if
you have the money and you really
feel that you want to improve
your appearance, then you know.
But is it an improvement?
I don't know.
It is a little fake.
Yeah, it is a little bit fake.
Like, for example, but it does help
people with their self-confidence, right?
Sometimes, for example, with the
case of breast implants, some women
feel very, very self-conscious
about them having smaller breasts.
So they want to get bigger
breasts and they feel more
confident, happier, and
you know, stuff like this.
So I guess if it helps and if you really
want it, you know, everyone's to their own.
Well, I'm curious what
our users think about this.
Have you had plastic surgery?
Would you like to have plastic surgery?
Let us know in our website, englishpot.com.
Right.
We'll see you guys there.
Until next time.
Bye.